Guide to the Josephine Jewell Dodge Papers, 1873-1874
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Josephine Jewell Dodge Papers
1873-1874
Dodge, Josephine Jewell, 1855-1928
0.2 cubic feet (1 box)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
37 letters and 1 fragment to Mary Strong from Josephine Jewell (Dodge) while at Vassar; 8 letters and 1 fragment to Strong from Jewell while in Russia; and one letter and one fragment to Strong by Josephine's sister, Florence Jewell, describing social life and travel in Russia, where their father, Marshall Jewell, was U.S. Minister in St. Petersburg.
Biographical Note
Josephine Marshall Jewell (1855-1928) entered Vassar in 1870 as a student in the preparatory department. She was a member of the college class of 1875, but she left in 1873 when her father, Marshall Jewell, was appointed minister to St. Petersburg by President Grant. The Jewell family lived in Russia for a year, where Josephine and her sister enjoyed a very gay social life. In 1873 Mr. Jewell was appointed Postmaster General, and the family returned to the United States. Josephine married Arthur M. Dodge in 1875, and became deeply interested in the child-care needs of working mothers. She was the founder of the Association of Day Nurseries of New York City in 1895, and three years later was the first president of the National Federation of Day Nurseries.
Scope and Content Note
37 letters and 1 fragment to Mary Strong from Josephine Jewell (Dodge) while at Vassar; 8 letters and 1 fragment to Strong from Jewell while in Russia; and one letter and one fragment to Strong by Josephine's sister, Florence Jewell, describing social life and travel in Russia, where their father, Marshall Jewell, was U.S. Minister in St. Petersburg.
Access
This collection is open for research according to the
regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library
without any additional restrictions.
Subject Headings
Names:
Strong, Mary; Jewell, Florence; Dodge, Arthur M.
Organizations:
Association of Day Nurseries of New York City
Places:
Soviet Union--Social life and customs; Soviet Union--Description and travel; Vassar College--Students
VCL Categories
Travel
Encoding Information
Encoded by Elizabeth Clarke, March 2007.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Percival Dodge, January 24, 1963.
Container List
- Letters from Josephine Jewell
  - Letters from Josephine Jewell at Vassar to Mary Strong, 1871; (13 letters) (Folder 1)
  - Letters from Josephine Jewell at Vassar to Mary Strong, 1871; (TS of above) (Folder 2)
  - Letters from Josephine Jewell at Vassar to Mary Strong, 1872, n.d.; (24 letters, 1 fragment, 1 poem) (Folder 3)
  - Letters from Josephine Jewell at Vassar to Mary Strong, 1872, n.d.; (TS of above) (Folder 4)
  - Letters from Josephine Jewell in St. Petersburg to Mary Strong, Sept. 1873, Apr. 1874, n.d.; (8 letters, 1 fragment) (Folder 5)
  - Letters from Josephine Jewell in St. Petersburg to Mary Strong, Sept. 1873, Apr. 1874, n.d.; (TS of above) (Folder 6)
  - Letters from Josephine Jewell in St. Petersburg to Mary Strong, Sept. 1873, Apr. 1874, n.d.; (TS of above) (Folder 7)
  - Letters from Josephine Jewell in St. Petersburg to Mary Strong, Sept. 1873, Apr. 1874, n.d.; (TS, carbons of above) (Folder 8)
- Letters from Florence Jewell
  - Letters from Florence Jewell in St. Petersburg to Mary Strong, Jan. 1874, n.d.; (1 letter, 1 fragment) (Folder 9)
  - Letters from Florence Jewell in St. Petersburg to Mary Strong, Jan. 1874, n.d.; (TS of above) (Folder 10)
  - Letters from Florence Jewell in St. Petersburg to Mary Strong, Jan. 1874, n.d.; (TS of above) (Folder 11)